My mom told me if you hang around nine
broke friends, you're going to be the 10th one, right?
So if I hang around nine guys that
drives Ferraris, I have a lot better chance.
What's going on, everyone? This is James
Doolin with the School of Hard Knocks,
and this is our first episode of
our new series, 10 Questions with Millionaires.
I'm here today with Levon Perrin, who's a millionaire.
He's an entrepreneur, business owner, savant, and man, we're so
pumped and thrilled to have him on as our first guest.
We'll start off with our first question.
What is the biggest thing that you would say that
really separates people apart from their peers in the business world,
whether it's a skill set or a mindset
thing for people to incorporate into their toolbox?
I think it goes back, and
you mentioned it. It's simply mindset.
I can almost end there. Mindset means everything, right?
If you take a situation and your mindset's
not right, you're going to think it's negative, right?
Because we live in, I mean, if
you pick up, if you watch the news,
is it a lot of positive
on the news? No, it's negative.
So we're fed a lot of negative
stuff. That's why I don't watch the news.
That keeps all the negative out of my mind.
I'm not going to sit here and watch all the
stuff that happened negatively and try to live my life,
but I believe your mindset
is just, I can't tell you.
If I had to take one tool, right, if I was building
a person, and you get to put tools inside of a person,
and you had one major tool
they can get, it would be mindset.
When you have the right mindset, you're able
to go a lot further than any other thing.
You want to know why you're
not where you want to be?
Well, when you start looking in the
mirror and realizing it's because of you,
and honestly take a deep look at it
and look at the other side of the coin,
you could have done something better in that situation
that maybe would have gave you a different life.
Go with a group, go with a group.
Big word now everywhere is side hustle, right?
So you can take that side
hustle and do it in the evenings.
So some of my people that live on the
East Coast, they buy a license in the West Coast.
That buys them three hours a day.
So instead of 8 o'clock in their time
where they can stop calling people 8 o'clock,
now they can call up.
They can work till 11.
So you can work 9 to 5, have
dinner, go to football practice with the kids,
come home and 8 o'clock start calling for three hours
in the West Coast and have a whole other career.
And once that career takes off, now you can get
out of that job, that full-time job that you had.
One of the coolest things to me about
like whenever I'm talking to business owners and entrepreneurs
is it seems like there was
always kind of a turning point,
whether it was when they were going to
school or when they were working throughout their career.
But what point in your life did you know that like
this was kind of the path that you wanted to take?
I think it was one of the things that
just kind of happened, to be honest with you.
Just going back and forth with the corporate
America didn't ever seem like I really fit.
It felt like I had a lot
of questions and I bucked the system,
but I was a good salesperson and
everyone liked me and I can lead people.
It just became where I felt like I
wanted to go ahead and do my own thing
and take all the tools that I've
learned though from working for other companies
and go and take it and
put it into action for myself.
So working for other companies definitely helped me.
Loved it.
I learned how businesses work and be
able to take some of those skills
and just use them to my advantage.
You know, one door closes, another one opens.
So it was just time for me
to decide to do my own thing.
One of the big turning points for me other than
that is, you know, I was in the car business.
Right. And everybody knows what happens in a car business.
Right. Four or five divorces, blah, blah, blah.
That's what happens.
So my biggest thing was I didn't want that,
but I wanted to be able to see my kids.
What would you say has been the biggest thing that's
enabled you to scale your business to what it is now?
Everyone wants to make $100,000 a year.
Right. So very few people are able to do that.
Well, probably because that's your goal.
If you had a plan and a goal to
make $500,000 a year and you failed at your goal,
you probably would still make $100,000 a year.
But it's having a plan to help get you there.
One thing I've done for myself is to
say, what if they had 10 of me?
All right. So that company or
that particular people I'm doing business with,
would they be happy that they had 10 of me?
And in my situation is yes.
So that's how you know you're on the right track.
Be accountable. Everything you do is accountable.
We're in the United States.
Everyone has the same options.
Why are you not successful?
That's up to you.
Right. Surround yourself with people
that's going to be successful.
Right.
When I go downstairs and I go in our
garage, how many four hours you thinking down there?
Right. It's a good amount.
How many portions are downstairs?
A lot.
I'm sorry, but my mom told me
if you hang around nine broke friends,
you're going to be the 10th one.
Right.
So if I hang around nine guys that drives Ferraris,
I have a lot better chance.
Right.
I've been driving Ferrari.
So, you know, whether that's your dream
or not, I'm just saying putting yourself
in better situations around people, that's why
I made the pivot to move downtown.
I want to be around people
that were doing things, having the lifestyle,
doing the things that I like to do,
and I want to be some of those people.
So now we're them.
Me and my wife tell each other all the time.
Our kids come over to like, y'all are them.
Yeah.
Y'all are them people we see all the time.
Well, you know, I guess so. Right.
But the good part about it is,
like I said, there's no practice life.
How important has taking risk been to the success
of you as an entrepreneur and a business owner?
There's no success without risk. Bottom line.
You're not going to be safe and live in your comfort
zone and do everything you want to do and be successful.
That's just not going to happen.
You have to take some calculated risk. Right.
And learn from your risk.
Can't continue to do the same
thing over and over and over again.
But you got to believe in yourself.
And educate yourself.
Become a better version of yourself.
When you do that, sometimes there's risk of payoff.
Sometimes they won't.
But you still have to believe in whatever that
you're doing that you can give it your all.
For someone pursuing the sales industry
in 2022, how can someone crush it?
Or what is the secret to sales?
I believe just personal development.
That's something I didn't do in my youth.
I didn't read books.
I didn't read books after college.
I went online classes when online classes wasn't cool.
Early 2000s.
I did online.
I got my degree.
But I believe that the
personal development side has been huge.
I think last year I read probably 15 books.
Right.
The year before, I didn't read very many.
So I think the personal development helped
me a lot because it helped me
validate some things that I
thought, but I didn't know why.
Why my thoughts were where they were.
Why my ambitions were focused here and not there.
So I believe that personal growth
and development is probably the biggest
things that I would do differently.
I would start doing personal development at a younger age.
What would you say have been the three
fundamental books that you think
every entrepreneur should read to really
help along their path of
self-improvement and development as an entrepreneur?
There's one that stands above and beyond.
Yeah. One that just has changed for me.
That's How to Think and Grow Rich.
That's the number one book.
That's by Napoleon Hill.
It told me about my things
that I was doing as a youth.
And how to take those focuses and those
energies and put them in a different place.
So to me, that's my biggest book.
My mentor actually reads that same book every September.
And he just told me the other
day that he's starting to read it.
So I'm excited because now I'm
going to start reading that book.
But that one did things for me.
I mean, you got Rich Dad Poor Dad that's big.
You got Go for No.
That's one of my favorite ones, too.
Just because it's fun. It's easy.
That's the biggest things for me is really just learning.
You learn who you are, who you want to be.
Validate some things for yourself of why you
are the way you are, why you think
the way you do.
As a business owner, what has
been the biggest challenge that you faced
throughout your time owning a business
and how did you overcome it?
I think one of the biggest challenges
is learning how to be a business owner.
Right.
Meaning understanding what it takes to be consistent,
learning what it takes to be
to try to make things where it works for you.
Knowing that you can have
ups and downs, ups and downs.
I mean, that's just what you're going to have.
I don't care what business you're in.
That's what you're going to have. And learning to budget.
Right. Put your money in certain places.
When to do this, when
to do that, how to grow.
And I learned from all the mistakes.
Right. So if you learn from your mistakes,
I believe that's one of
the biggest things you can do.
Learn to that you're going to make
some mistakes and not be scared and overanalyze.
Right. Because I'm analytical.
The next guy.
But a lot of times people
overanalyze situations and then they don't move.
Right.
It's paralysis by analysis is what
a lot of people call it.
What has been the worst financial
decision that you've ever made?
I look at decisions and
things that don't go your way.
Not really as a negative.
It's kind of like playing a game, playing sports.
You don't necessarily lose.
You learn. So I believe that
things I've done in the past financially.
One of the things that I've done
financially, I've always wanted a 750 BMW
ever since I grew up in Germany mainly.
So I've always wanted a 750.
I had opportunity to own two of them.
Neither one of them.
And I remember a mechanic that was here
in Austin, kind of by the domain before.
The domain was even there, told me that if
I buy one of those, me and him would be
good friends because he knew I'd see him a lot.
But so that was something I
did that I probably shouldn't have done.
But I'm glad I did it.
But I should have done it differently
with a maintenance plan and just did it better.
So it wasn't a horrible decision.
How do you incorporate the work
life balance into your everyday life?
The only thing different between people
that are successful and not successful is
the ability to handle things because
of how they look at it.
So when people I love when.
People tell me, oh, I don't have time.
I don't have time. I don't have time.
I always think I said we
have this guy who runs Amazon.
I wonder what kind of how
much time in the day he has.
So the amount of things he's able to
accomplish in the same amount of time that
me and you have.
Why do we not have time?
He has time because he's smarter with his time.
He puts people around him that's able to help
him do more in a shorter period of time.
They say if you want
to go somewhere fast, go alone.
If you want to go somewhere for a long time.
For someone who's been
very successful financially, do you
personally think money buys happiness?
It can buy freedom if you
know what to do with it.
Right. If you know how
to handle it, if you learn,
if you grow, if you learn how to
how to do the right things with your money,
it's a good chance that you can
be happy, but not everybody that's happy is
are successful. So it's just I don't know.
It's that's a good question. Right.
But I think each individual has
to answer that question for themselves.
What buys happiness? Right.
I mean, that's the first thing everyone says.
Oh, I had a million dollars. I'll be happy.
Right.
Well, I mean, if you can't manage a thousand dollars,
then you can't manage a million dollars. Right.
So learn to manage that thousand that you have.
Episode one of asking 10 questions to millionaires.
We just finished up here, downtown Austin with Lavon Perrin.
Lavon, thank you so much again for your time.
Appreciate you having us.
Thanks for the hospitality.
Allowed us to come up in a
like we said, podcast coming soon with Lavon.
Lots of great new content on the way.
So we just can't wait to
get after it and keep things rolling.
And like and subscribe.
School of Hard Knocks.
Give us a follow on everything. We appreciate you.
All right. Take care.